[narrator] Three days remain
until the sorting.
In the palace,
the King has completed his recovery
and plays Gungi without rest.
That's checkmate.
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
GUNGI X OF X KOMUGI
-We will resume in half a day.
-Huh?
But I can keep playing if you want me to.
I would take no joy in defeating you
while you're in this weakened state.
Go recover your strength.
This woman is a liability.
If this continues,
she will certainly cause problems.
[Komugi groans softly]
Well, if there's nothing else,
then I'll be going now.
So he could defeat the Gungi champion
at her peak.
So he could demonstrate his prowess.
as someone whom the King
was never able to best.
I'm such a fool!
I almost let a thoughtless impulse
leave a hideous,
irreparable scar on the King!
What was I thinking?
I shall pay for this with my life
once I ensure that the King
will rule the world.
[wailing]
Hmm?
[Knuckle] Seven people
will infiltrate the palace
Ikalgo, and finally Morel.
A few seconds after us,
the Chairman will enter
from outside Pitou's En.
During that time,
we all need to try to lure the Royal Guard
as far from the King as we can.
First up, Ikalgo, Killua, and Gon.
When we suddenly appear
in the middle of the palace,
They'll be in a tight formation.
Breaking it won't be easy.
Hmm, and that's where I come into play.
[grunts]
[imperceptible]
Okay. You got any questions?
[Gon] Uh, so about Palm…
I'm almost certain that she would take it
as an insult to her resolve.
-[sighs]
-[Knuckle] Hey, take it easy, will you?
Gon's just concerned about her is all.
And that would make us just like moths
flying straight into the heart
of a burning flame.
We would be dead on arrival.
But instead of worrying about
a bunch of worst-case scenarios,
let's trust Palm
to do whatever she has to.
All that makes sense if you ask me,
but I think what Gon is trying to say here
is that if Palm really has met such a fate
we still have time to change the plan.
it might cause the entire operation
to completely fall apart.
We still have two days,
plenty of time for Palm to contact us.
Meow-kay. Understood.
[King] Should I have tried
to escape to the right, perhaps?
[Komugi] You should've moved your knight.
You see,
I didn't want to let a single piece
control the center of the board.
you won't ever be able
to make me hesitate.
[sighs] Being passive is foreign to me.
-[Shaiapouf] Sire.
-What do you want?
[Shaiapouf] I have intel
for your ears only.
[gasps]
[King] It's fine. Speak.
Two days remain until the national rally.
The number of citizens
to process in the capital
Your point? I suggest you get to it.
[Shaiapouf] Very well, sire.
I would like to move up
the post-sorting schedule.
[King] That's all? Do as you wish.
[Menthuthuyoupi chuckles]
So you were chased out too.
We just need to wait for the King to win
and it'll be fine.
-[Shaiapouf] No.
-What?
A minute ago, you said you did.
What changed your mind?
The King is improving
at a remarkable rate,
but she is evolving as well.
So I'm no longer able to predict
the outcome of this contest.
[Neferpitou] I'm 100% sure
he's acting completely alone…
the man who defeated Leol.
Reports from Welfin and the others
confirm that the soldiers he controls
are all smoke puppets.
They don't move like Nen puppets,
Unfortunately, I can't leave my post yet.
Maybe he'll come to me. [groans]
[Knuckle] It's just about time
for us to enter the capital.
The enemy should have noticed
Morel's distraction by now
At the same time we're doing that,
then everyone'll think assassins
are hidden somewhere among the citizens,
[King] She attacks where I'm weak
without hesitation.
She's getting even sharper as we play.
Two-one-one, cavalry.
Okay, six-six-one, captain.
[King] But it's not suffocating.
In fact, I find this enjoyable,
because she's guiding me
into that style of play.
But that only goes to show
that she is still far above me in skill.
Dear leader, I feel…
I feel weird.
It just isn't stopping.
No matter what I do,
all these wonderful moves
keep flooding into my head.
If I try,
I'm sure that I can become even better.
[King] She's awakened?
That can only mean…
She's about to get stronger.
That's checkmate.
Is there something wrong?
No. I'd like to go back
to my room for a bit
around the game board. That's all.
When I touch the pieces
after they're placed,
I never forget their position.
It just stays in my head.
[King] Every move she's ever played?
-Fine. You're excused.
-[Komugi] Thank you.
[King] A foolish question.
Her name.
Hey.
Your name? What should I call you by?
[Komugi] You mean me, sire?
[King] Is there anyone else here?
Um, my name is Komugi, dear leader!
Komugi, huh?
Hmm.
[Komugi] Dear leader,
if it isn't too forward of me to ask,
I wonder if you'd mind
telling me your name.
[King gasps]
My name?
What?
What is it?
Sire. I am at your service.
-Pouf.
-Yes.
-[King] Youpi.
-Yes, sire.
Is anything the matter, sire?
-[King] Pouf.
-Wha…
That's right. You are known as Pouf.
Hmm, so then tell me, what is my name?
and then the entire world will know that
there is but one true and rightful king.
[King] That assumes
the others can be eliminated.
Your thoughts, Youpi?
Your question is far beyond my capacity,
so as much as I'd love to answer it, sire,
I don't know.
-[King] Pitou?
-Hmm.
I'm sure that
whatever your feelings are in the matter,
they greatly outweigh my own.
If I could make a suggestion,
perhaps you should select the name that
you find the most pleasing to your ear.
Hmm. Very well, then.
[eagle screeches]
[Shaiapouf] You can choose a name
after the sorting is complete.
For the time being, our top priority
is to finish all the preparations
Mmm.
Is something wrong, sire?
[Shaiapouf] He bothered to learn her name?
[King] She has awakened.
Komugi will now become much stronger,
-Pitou.
-Yes.
If Komugi were to endure the sorting,
the same kind as what will occur tomorrow,
what would happen to her?
She would die, sire.
…I ended a child's life.
[Shaiapouf] Sire, you mustn't say it!
[King] It's possible that the child…
[Shaiapouf] Please,
this isn't becoming of you.
[King] …possessed the raw potential
to surpass me in a particular field.
[Shaiapouf] The king must be absolute.
[King] Yet I extinguished it.
[Shaiapouf] Do not repent your actions.
I had no real reason, not a single one.
[Shaiapouf] That's enough, sire.
You mustn't say any more!
[Shaiapouf gasps]
[eagle screeches]
-[King laughing]
-[gasps]
[laughs]
So that must mean
that I have tremendous power.
I appear without warning
to rob countless beings
of their inferior strength.
To crush, to destroy.
Violence is my power,
[Neferpitou] Why?
[Shaiapouf] I jumped
to the wrong conclusion
and came within a hair's breadth
of insulting the King.
I foolishly believed
that His Highness regretted his actions,
If the girl impedes the King,
then we've got no choice but to kill her.
[shudders] To think that my mind works
on the exact same level as yours.
Komugi, that female is no different.
Her skill is in Gungi,
a simple board game.
So her life is subject to my whim.
If I but change my mind,
I can crush her immediately.
The goal was simply to kill time
before the selection,
She's worthless to me.
Let's kill her right now.
[King] Why didn't you call for help?
Look here and here.
There's blood all over you!
People might still be sleeping,
and I didn't want to bother them.
But you wouldn't have bothered
anyone at all.
What?
You are a guest of the King.
What am I saying?
I came here to kill her, didn't I?
[King] What is this creature?
And me…
What do I want to do with her?
[sobbing continues]
[closing theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[upbeat music playing]
[Killua] Then we're all set
for future preview segments.